psychologyjunkie.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy - Psychology Junkie

Your privacy is very important to us. At Psychology Junkie we have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site.

It is Psychology Junkie’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Psychology Junkie collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Psychology Junkie’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Psychology Junkie’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Psychology Junkie may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Psychology Junkie also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on our blogs. Psychology Junkie only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Psychology Junkie’s websites choose to interact with Psychology Junkie in ways that require the site to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Psychology Junkie gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who comment on our blog to provide a username and email address. Those who wish to receive Psychology Junkie updates via email, we collect their emails. In each case, Psychology Junkie collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Psychology Junkie. Psychology Junkie does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Your Choices**

Access, Correction, Deletion

We respect your privacy rights and provide you with reasonable access to the Personally-Identifying Information that you may have provided through your use of the services we provide.  If you wish to amend any Personally-Identifying Information we hold about you, or to request that we delete any information about you that we have obtained from an Integrated Service, you may contact us as set forth in the “How to Contact Us” section.  At your request, we will have any reference to you deleted or blocked in our database.

You may update, correct, or delete your information and preferences at any time by contacting us as set forth in the “How to Contact Us” section.  Please note that any changes you request will be made within a reasonable period of time, we may retain all information you submit for backups, archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, analytics, satisfaction of legal obligations, or where we otherwise reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so.

You may decline to share certain Personally-Identifying Information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functions of our site.

At any time, you may object to the processing of your Personally-Identifying Information, on legitimate grounds, except if otherwise permitted by applicable law.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Psychology Junkie may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Psychology Junkie may monitor the most popular pages or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. Psychology Junkie may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Psychology Junkie does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Psychology Junkie discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Psychology Junkie’s behalf or to provide services available at Psychology Junkie’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Psychology Junkie will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Psychology Junkie discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Psychology Junkie believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Psychology Junkie, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Psychology Junkie website and have supplied your email address, Psychology Junkie may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Psychology Junkie and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Psychology Junkie takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Psychology Junkie uses cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of Psychology Junkie website, and their website access preferences. Psychology Junkie visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Psychology Junkie’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Psychology Junkie’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Email Addresses**

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, or enter a promotion.  We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the Site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.] 

**Ads**

**Interest-Based Advertising**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners.You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

**For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

**Transactional Data**

We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our Site. The Transactional Data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions.  [Payment processing on our Site is handled by our payment services providers,  _Paypal, Shopify, or Teachabl_. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at:  
https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full  
https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy  
https://teachable.com/privacy-policy

**Comments**

Comments and other content submitted to Akismet anti-spam service are not saved on our servers unless they were marked as false positives, in which case we store them long enough to use them to improve the service to avoid future false positives.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Psychology Junkie may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Psychology Junkie’s sole discretion. Psychology Junkie encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

**How To Contact Us**

If you at any time you would like to contact us to access, correct, delete, object to, or request restriction of data processing, please go to the “Contact Me” page, linked in the website header, and submit your request for action.

## Disclosure

In 2015, the **_[Federal Trade Commission released their new rules for Disclosure Compliance](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/ftcs-endorsement-guides-what-people-are-asking)_**[. ](http://www.business.ftc.gov/sites/default/files/pdf/bus41-dot-com-disclosures-information-about-online-advertising.pdf)These rules are set in place to ensure that readers or viewers of web media (blogs, Youtube videos, etc.) know if the blogger/presenter is sponsored, endorsed, or partnered with a different company. In blog terms, the readers need to know if the blogger is making money by sharing a link or product.

**In compliance with the FTC guidelines, please assume the following about links and posts on this site:  Any/all of the links on PsychologyJunkie.com are affiliate links from which I receive a small compensation from sales of certain items.**

__**What are affiliate links?**__  
Purchases are made on external affiliate company websites: When a reader clicks on an affiliate link located on Psychologyjunkie.com to purchase an item, the reader buys the item from the seller directly (not from Psychology Junkie).  Amazon and/or other companies pay Psychology Junkie a small commission or other compensation for promoting their website or products through their affiliate program.

**Prices are exactly the same for you if your purchase is through an affiliate link or a non-affiliate link. ​You will  not pay more by clicking through to the link. **

I use two main types of affiliate programs:

**1. _Amazon affiliate links._  **  
Psychology Junkie is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon properties including, but not limited to, amazon.com, endless.com, myhabit.com, smallparts.com, or amazonwireless.com.  Amazon offers a small commission on products sold through their affiliate links. Each of your purchases via our Amazon affiliation links supports our cause at _no additional cost to you_.

Amazon and the Amazon logo are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates.  
​  
If a blogger links to an Amazon product (with a special code for affiliates embedded in the link), and a reader places an item in their “shopping cart” through that link within 24 hours of clicking the link, the blogger gets a small percentage of the sale.  Amazon links are not “pay per click.”  If you click on the product link and stay around Amazon and purchase something else, however, I will get commission on that sale.

Anytime you see a link that looks like www.amazon.com/….  
​it may be an Amazon affiliate link.

**2.   _Product affiliate links._  **  
These affiliate links work the same way: if you click the link and buy the product, then the blogger gets a percentage of the sale or some other type of compensation. Again, prices are not different if you use these affiliate links. You will _not_ pay more by clicking through to the link. These links are not “pay per click.”

Psychology Junkie  
2609 Victoria Ave #1181  
Bellevue, NE, 6805  
http://www.psychologyjunkie.com

### Subscribe to Typology Tuesday

Want to discover more about personality type? Get the inside scoop with Susan Storm on all things typological, along with special subscriber freebies, and discounts on new eBooks and courses! Join Typology Tuesday today!
